# NAVDEEP SINGH BEDI

#### **PROFILE**

A software aficionado having around 7 years of experience in Mobile Application development and Core Java. Initiated ReactNative development at Appster Ltd. An enthusiastic team player and deep creative thinker. In my free time, I blog and enjoy time with family.

#### CONTACT

PHONE:

+91-9971100991

EMAIL:

navdeep.droid@gmail.com

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/navdeepdroid

MEDIUM:

medium.com/@navdeepsinghbedi

### **SKILLS**

Java Kotlin

JavaScript

ReactNative

ReactJS

MVVM, MVP

Room Persistence

**SQLite** 

Google Map/Places APIs

Firebase

Android JetPack

Retrofit

Glide/Piccaso

EventBus

Dagger 2

### **PROJECTS**

Agrichain
Punjabi Radio USA
TaxiNet Rider
Mind Body Session
Jetzy

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Sr Software Designer

NatWest Markets (Royal Bank of Scotland) • Gurugram, India 06/2019 – 04/2021

- Designed and coded applications in an agile environment utilizing a test-driven development approach
- Created and maintained project schedule and technical documentation and acted as liaison between business, QA, and development team
- Worked on an extended project in React Js for managerial monitoring.

# Software Engineer (Android) Agrichain Pvt Ltd • Gurugram, India

06/2018 - 05/2020

The company dealt with providing technical solutions for agricultural organizations using Blockchain.

Collaborated to create efficient applications for the agricultural industry that will assist respective stakeholders in making better-informed decisions. Strategize to reduce needless paperwork, minimize supply chain inefficiency, and risk, and provide a single medium to conduct business

# Software Engineer (Android) Appster LLP • Gurugram, India

10/2015 - 06/2018

Appster was an Australian app development company. It developed mobile, web apps for startups, public figures, and enterprises.

- Oversaw the development and architectural activities for multiple Native Android applications.
- Spearheaded initiation of React-Native application development at the organization.
- Provided in house technical trainings.

# Software Engineer (Android) Icreon Communications - Noida, India

11/2014 - 10/2015

- Prepared specific Java programs based on clients' requirements.
- Added Java batch programs to improve the quality of the application.
- Debugged existing Java programs and resolved the existing issues in the system.

### **EDUCATION**

#### Seneca College – Toronto, Canada

2021-Current

Postgraduate Certification, Business Analytics

## Visvesvaraya Technological University – Bidar, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology